A Guide to the Miscellaneous Oversize Collection, 1958-2007
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Miscellaneous Oversize Collection, 1958-2007
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-43
1 box: 3.75" x 20.25" x 24.25" and one box 3.75" x 16.5" x 20.5," 40 items
Historical Collections
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The items were donated by various individuals. Some are oversize items are from the 8th Evacuation Hospital collection, the Kerr White collection, or the Tom Hunter papers.
Scope and Content
This collection includes prints, drawings, architectural documents, and posters.
Arrangement
The arrangement of the items is mainly by weight with the heavier items on the bottom of the boxes and the lighter ones on top.
Contents List
- "Saturday Evening Post", 1944 November 11, 6 pages (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Includes ads that promote recruitment of men and women to serve during WWII. One is by Eastman Kodak to promote the U.S. Cadet Nurse Corps titled "We feel awfully good about Mary's joining the U.S. Cadet Nurse Corps." There is also an ad, "To the Ladies" (WAVE, WAC, SPAR, Marine, Cadet Nurse) by Canada Dry. A third is called "Pride of the Fleet!" by the Electric Boat Company. Donated by Karen Fankhauser 3/26/2013.
- "Saturday Evening Post" ?, [1943-44?], 2 pages (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  One side is an ad by Eastman Kodak to promote the U.S. Cadet Nurse Corps titled "I signed up the very week I graduated." On the other side is an ad by Tide Water Associated titled "The oil that's poison ... to the Japs." Donated by Karen Fankhauser 3/26/2013.
- Kerr White on retiring as Chairman of NIH Health Services Research Study Section drawn by Broering, 1966, 1 drawing (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Formerly shelved 16/012
- William Osler drawn by L.L. Fischman, undated, 1 drawing (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  The print is #269 out of 300
- Mark of Commendation by the Navy Department to University of Virginia Department of Medicine, undated, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Formerly shelved 13/038; Commendation given for cooperating with the U.S. Navy in training officer candidates under the Navy V-12 Program during WWII
- U.S. Navy Bureau of Medicine and Surgery Certificate of Achievement to University of Virginia Department of Medicine, undated, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Formerly shelved 13/013; Commendation given for cooperating with the U.S. Navy Medical Department during WWII
- Conceiving Pregnancy, Creating Mothers, 1993 March 26-27, 1 poster (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
- Mr. Jefferson's Anatomical Hall, University of Virginia, undated, 4 prints, color with ribbon (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  One print is signed by E. W. Pullen to Milton Rosenberg
- UVa School of Medicine class plays, 1979-1994, 10 posters, color (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  West Five Story, 1978; Animal House Officer, 1979; The Ileus and the Oddity, 1983; Trivial Pursuit: Tales of the Scutbusters, 1985; Real to Reel, 1986; 60 Beats, [1987]; From the Far Side: Late Night with Dr. Letterman, 1988; On the Road to Wizdom...Against All Oz, 1989; Lost in the Link, 1990; Health Care Reform School 1994
- "2300 Years of Medical Clothing" by Warja Honneger-Lavater, [19--], 10 matted engravings, color (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  We have 10 of the 12 engravings in the set: I. Greek Physician; II. Physician of Rome during the Empire; III. Surgeon, 14th Century; IV. Apothecary, 15th Century; VI. Physician, 15th Century; VII. Surgeon, 16th Century; VIII. Physician, 16th Century; IX. Nurse, 16th Century; X. Physician, 17th Century; XI. Surgeon, 18th Century
- A History of Medicine in Pictures Presented by Parke, Davis & Company, 1958-1964, prints (color) suitable for framing and text (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Directed by George A. Bender, Paintings by Robert A. Thom; background information about the historical events illustrated in this series of pictures is presented also.
- Roanoke College, Salem, Va. Drawn from nature by A. Hoen & Co., undated, 1 print (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
  Formerly shelved P12/004
- University of Virginia Medical School by J. M. Benitez, 1984, 1 color print (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
  In folder with Hunter written on it. Probably from the Tom Hunter collection.
- Medical School Sketch by Don Swann, 1981, June 30, 1 pencil drawing (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
  The print, #1 out of 300, was a gift to Tom Hunter, and is signed by many of Dr. Hunter's colleagues.
- 8th Evacuation Hospital, Pietramala, Italy, 1944, undated, 1 drawing (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
  Formerly shelved as P8/005
- "The Four Doctors" by John Singer Sargent, undated, 1 black and white matted print (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
  Originally done in 1906, the print features William H. Welch, William S. Halsted, William Osler and Howard A. Kelly. Dr. C. L. Gemmill is written on the back.
- United States Map of Ambulatory Sentinel Practice Sites, 1988 September 17, 1 map (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
  The map was given to Kerr White on his retirement from the ASPN Board at the Annual ASPN Convocation, Denver, Co. It has the signatures of ASPN practitioners.
- Medical Education Building, 95% Construction Documents, volume 1 of 2, 2007 March 20, 1 collection of architectural drawings (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
- "Agreed Rate of Medical Charges" fee bill, copy of 1848 original, 3 color, full-size copies (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
- "New System of Anatomy," Dictionary entry from an unknown text, undated, circa 1750-1799, 4 pages (Box-folder 02 [oversize])
  The source of this entry is unknown; however, the text is similar to an entry for "Anatomy" that appears in 'The Complete Dictionary of Arts and Sciences: In Which the Whole of Human Learning is Explained, and the Difficulties Attending the Acquisition of Every Art, Whether Liberal or Mechanical, are Removed, in the Most Easy and Familiar Manner,' by Temple Henry Croker, Thomas Williams, and Samuel Clark, 1764-1766. Gift of Elizabeth Mandell, MD.